Fairfax, VA 22031 (818) 671-8222 christopherdenq@gmail.com

CHRISTOPHER DENO

cdenq.github.io github.com/cdenq linkedin.com/in/christopherdenq

SUMMARY

Experienced in fullstack software development, data analytics, machine learning, and database engineering. Unique background in **art market** confers better data-driven storytelling and strong understanding of product impact within business environments. **Avid self-learner** and **serial project-builder** who strives to constantly grow, **empower others**, and add value to the world.

EDUCATION

Foothill College Los Altos Hills, CA

Visiting Student / Associates of Science in Mathematics and Computer Science

Present

• Course Topics: OOP Programming, Statistics/Probability, Linear Algebra, Multivariate Calculus, Cloud Computing

University of Pennsylvania, School of Engineering and Applied Sciences, College of Arts and Sciences

Philadelphia, PA

Bootcamp Certificate in Data Analytics and Visualization

March 2022

Bachelor of Arts, Double Major in Philosophy and Art History

May 2021

- Honors: John C. Parker Fellowship, 2016 (\$500 for statistical research in game theory)
- Course Topics: Machine Learning, Big Data Analytics, Database Management, Fullstack Development

SELECTED PROJECTS (More on GitHub)

Full-Stack Machine Learning Web-App: Mushroom Edibility Predictor

Full-Stack Interactive Web Dashboard: Market Metrics on Video Game Industry

March 2022

Python (SKLearn, Flask, Matplotlib), HTML/CSS/JS github.com/cdenq/mushroom-edibility-predictor-web-app

• Full-stack web app that utilizes mushroom data to predict edibility of mushrooms with user inputted features

• Trained 7 ML models on 60k+ data points to predict its edibility to within 80-99% accuracy, created 8 EDA graphs

January 2022

Python (Flask), MongoDB, HTML/CSS/JavaScript

github.com/cdenq/video-game-performance-scraper-and-web-dashboard

- Full-stack web app that scraped market metrics on the video game industry and visualized on dashboard
- Analyzed 10k data points, maintained 5 MongoDB collections, created 19 visualizations

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

PNC Financial Services Group

Incoming Summer Data Analyst Intern

Harrisburg, PA | Remote

June 2022 – Aug 2022

- Will analyze data metrics, create statistical models, and present findings to supervising team to impact business operations
- Will work extensively with software via Python, SQL, Tableau; opportunity to develop for AI/ML department

California State University: Northridge, College of Engineering and Computer Science

Northridge, CA

Fall/Spring Machine Learning Research Assistant

November 2021 – May 2022

- Researched graduate-level ML material, created 12+ class slide decks, 10+ Python code samples; assisted with curriculum
- Succeeded in researching, designing, and coding for graduate-level ML course with Professor Wen-chin Hsu

2U - Trilogy Education Services, Wyzant.com, Local

Various

Incoming 2U Data Analytics Teaching Assistant, Wyzant AP Computer Science Tutor, Volunteer Tutor

Sep 2021 – Present

- Will teach/tutor for Georgia Tech Data Analytics bootcamp as 2U Teaching Assistant for summer session
- Taught computer science to 25+ students for 65+ hours: from coding fundamentals to data structures to ML topics
- Succeeded in adapting teaching style, clearly communicating abstract computer science concepts, mentoring students

Christie's Auctions & Private Sales

New York, NY

Summer Intern

June 2020 – August 2020

- Contributed to 6+ reports, appraisals, and collection package documentation; attended 3+ onsite auctions, hilling meetings
- Succeeded in helping Christie's adjust to accelerated digital marketplace and understand its market role amidst pandemic

SKILLS AND FRAMEWORKS

Languages: OOP Python, Java, R, SQL (PostgreSQL), NoSQL (MongoDB), HTML/CSS/JS
 Libraries/Frameworks: SKLearn, Keras, TensorFlow, PyTorch, Pandas, RESTful APIs, web-scraping

• Cloud Tools: Hadoop/Spark, Docker, GCP Cloud Run, Google Collab, Git, AWS

• Visualization Tools: Tableau, Excel/VBA, Google Sheets/Google Apps Script

HOBBIES